[Music]
注：Secret Informant意思是秘密线人，但是内容都是美食
one of the things I learned on our trip
在这次亚洲之旅中让我印象深刻的一样东西是
to Asia is how much care and attention
美味的料理都是在简单的食材上花很多心思制作出来的
注：中文字幕是官方字幕，未经过修改，而英文字幕和中文字幕的时间轴没对齐，
好像还只是自动英文字幕……看看中文就好了
can go into many seemingly simple
ingredients things like rice or a
像是米饭或是某些特别调配的酱料
注：旁白是techlinked的Riley，本视频上传于20180824
special sauce or just noodles how many
或是面条
有哪次你吃面条的时候是一口气吃完的
times have you had a noodle dish where
you just shovel it down as fast as you
can
在香港的刘森记面家
well at Lao some key noodle in Hong Kong
这里的面条好吃的让你能够一口闷
you can certainly do that but these
不过这里的美味更加值得细细品尝
dishes invite you to savor them a little
more the noodles are handmade by the
刘森记的面条都是由老板亲自手工制作
owner of the restaurant
Chung he learned how to make them from
面条的制作工艺则是从刘老板的爷爷这里
his dad who was taught by his dad we're
代代家传到现在的
我们会在下一集视频里介绍面条的制作细节以及历史
gonna take a closer look at the methods
and history of how these noodles are
made in the next video for now our old
现在有请我们的老朋友 Stanley
friend and Tattler for this episode
Stanley get some insight into what we're
和刘老板交流一下我们接下来会吃什么
about to eat from the chef
这家面馆在我家传承三代人了
我的爷爷最开始开了这个生意
那时候是在一九四几年的广州
到现在已经有将近六七十年了
店里最主要是卖馄饨面
还有卖手工蛋面
我听说你们店里的虾子面非常有名
在我爸这一代经营这家面馆的时候
并没有卖很多虾子面
是因为当时虾子很贵 所以虾子面
只保留给对我们这里熟悉的常客点
菜单上是找不到这道虾子面的
当我继承了这家面馆之后
我便正式开始卖这道特别的面点
不过呢虾子必须和鸡蛋面一起吃
我们的馄饨也是用传统老工艺制作的
我们会用芝麻粉炒比目鱼肉
先是炒比目鱼肉
然后把炒好的鱼肉打成碎粉状
而且我们也会把芝麻炒过之后加在里面打成粉
非常感谢你能够保留传统的制作工艺
这样的传统工艺越来越少见了
感谢您接受采访
这家店叫什么名字
It's called Lau Sum Kee. So Lau it's
这家店叫做刘森记
刘是老板的姓
basically the last name of the owner the
这里是面馆所以特色当然是面条
specialty here is obviously noodles and
放在我们面前的有两种面条
in front of you there are two sources
一个是汤面
music one is the noodle soup when it's
另一个是虾子捞面
actually dry noodles with shrimp rose on
和什么东西
it okay
虾子啦
from a shrimp roe sharone oh yeah so
就是烘干的虾子
like dried shrimp eggs but anyways crazy
面条是刘森记的特色
noodles are the specialty direct
这种面条从广东话翻译成英语是叫竹升面
translation from Cantonese suspendu
noodles but there's definitely new
不过面里面是没有竹子的
bamboo in in these noodles so the
面条是面粉和鸭蛋混合做成的
noodles are made of flour and duck eggs
这个面家在这里传承了三代人
so this place to survive for three
generations solely on bamboo noodles so
就是因为这里的竹升面
they followed the traditional way of
他们用传统工艺制作馄饨
making one ton for you that's true it's
说的没错
如果没有馄饨就不叫馄饨汤了
not wonton soup without the wontons yeah
我先来尝尝这汤底
I would like to get a little bit of that
broth first actually
oh I think a lot of time when you have
很多次尝到鱼汤的时候
like a fish base broth that can seem
会怕汤太浓
kind of a bit overpowering like that
就会有很浓的鱼腥味
like it can be really fishy this is like
这鱼汤则是淡淡的
just it's like the play yeah if you like
这样调配的口味很好
a nice a nice little mix of everything
that's in there to the noodles to the
开始吃面条
noodles from what we eating here is
我们现在吃的是有点泡软的面条
probably a softer version of the bamboo
your nose because it's been still
在我们说话的时候面条吸收了很多汤汁
finishing for a bunch of time Bob would
owe me okay a lot of time when you have
很多时候吃汤面
noodles and soup there it becomes so
面条会因为泡在汤里时间太久而变得非常软
soft because they've been sitting on it
for so long but these seem to have
不过这面条还保留了他们原有的嚼劲
retained a little bit of their yeah how
用有嚼劲来形容很贴切
did the character that's a rabbit I'm
我要来尝尝馄饨
gonna eat the wonton okay yeah I'm gonna
go boiled on time we break into this
这馄饨一级棒
这面皮咬下去的时候口感有一点特别
like a nice nice subtle little wrapping
flavor so long okay well let's see how
就一点点点
接着里面就有点咸了
我们来试试看这道面点吧
we do up against this one noodles shrimp
面条 虾子 和 猪肘
roe pork knuckle
hello shrimp I'm meeting your baby's
哈喽 虾子们
我要吃你的后代了
little babies I'm gonna go I'm gonna go
我先来试试这猪肘
for this first actually the Pig knuckle
我要这几样一起吃
猪肘煮的很嫩了
is is just like tendon it's like it's
有点像
it's sort of like a jelly but it gives a
有点像果冻
不过咬下去的时候却很有嚼劲
lot more resistance when you're biting
into it it's got this like hard salty
有这种咸咸的厚实肉感
meaty taste I think the shrimp roe also
这些虾子也挺咸的
in itself is quite salty it is the fact
是的哦
他们被打的很碎 几乎就是粉状
that it's also like so tiny that it's
kind of like a powder it it really helps
能很好的衬托出捞面的口感
with the whole fact that this is dry
noodles like it makes it so much more
让原本就比较干的捞面吃起来更干
more Drive they kind of dehydrate the
这些虾子有经过脱水
the ingredients right the way for
这是中华料理中让食物的鲜美更加精纯的一种方式
Chinese to
Central Asia it really lends like a
这种口感很奇特
really interesting texture to it yeah
like I haven't really had it kind of
我从来没有吃过这种上面有一层干粉的捞面
noodles where there's like a dry powder
on it yeah when you brought the dish out
这道面条上来的时候表面一层粉
it looked like a powder but when you eat
当你吃的时候
it you almost like feel every single
你几乎可以感觉到一粒一粒的虾子
little grain grease every little bro
Stanley 非常感谢
family gentleman thank you thank you
it's a wonderful and thank you for
这很棒
感谢你观看这一集的 Secret Informant
watching this episode of secret
informant subscribe if you liked it
如果你觉得好看就订阅吧
接下来会有很多内容哦
because we got a lots more coming out
really thanks again thanks for watching
再次感谢你 Stanley
没问题
再会啦
感谢你观看这一期的视频
this video it's produced by tattle
这一集由 Tattle 制作
如果你还不知道
if you don't know tattle is a platform
Tattle 是帮助冒险者连接本地向导的一个网络平台
connecting savvy locals with curious
explorers check us out on social media
来我们的社交媒体上看看
用视频下面的链接订阅 Tattle 的每周电子期刊
and sign up for the newsletter at the
link in the description
感谢刘森记面家协助我们这一集的拍摄
big thanks to Lao some key noodle for
having us and thanks to Stanley for
也感谢 Stanley 作为这一集的嘉宾
being our Tattler for this episode make
订阅我们的频道看更多视频哟
sure to subscribe to tattle for more
videos from secret informant